Daniel Enrico

(916)719-8446 thedanielenrico@gmail.com Sacramento, CA Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in music and education with a lifelong dedication to learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among peers for strong work ethic and attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project.

Technical Skills

Skills: Fast learner, hardworking, reliable, excellent time management, creative thinker *Languages*: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Frameworks/Libraries: Bootstrap, React.js, Vue.js, jQuery, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, MySQL,

Handlebars.js, GitHub, Version Control, Command Line, Slack

Projects

MyGradeBook

A user-friendly gradebook designed for teachers to share feedback and assignments with students Worked with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Sequelize, and our own API's As this was a team project, challenges included version control, naming conventions, and data structuring

Hangman

An online game built with JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

Faced multiple challenges including verifying user input against the word to guess and rendering/updating letter tiles during the game

Learned RegEx concepts and DOM manipulation

FriendFinder

An online questionnaire to connect users based on compatibility

Used MySQL to create a database to store users data and used JavaScript to match users to one another

Education

UC Davis Extension

Full Stack Web Development Certificate of Completion June 2019

American River College

Music Performance Major 2011-2013

Reliance Christian Academy

High School Diploma 2011

Experience

Website Management

Becky's Flowers, Roseville, CA January 2019-present

-Develop new product pages and update existing ones

-Organize and format media for display on the website

Private Music Teacher

Music Lab, Sacramento, CA

CB Music, Roseville, CA

June 2018-present
August 2014-present

-Manage and maintain a roster of 25 or more students

-Create personalized lesson plans for each student to meet their goals

Barista

The Mill Sacramento, Sacramento, CA April 2016- October 2018
Insight Coffee Roasters, Sacramento, CA January 2015 - April 2016